# Frontend Developer Gloria Dias

Montreal, Canada

+1 514 999 7208 | gloriadias123@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/gloria-dias

Spoken Languages: English, Hindi

## **PROFILE**

Information Technology engineer with a passion for Full Stack Web Development with experience using front-end technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and back-end technologies such as Node.js, with excellent problem-solving, collaboration, and communication skills. Revamped a website, resulting in a 55% increase in user engagement and traders for a leading FinTech firm. I am always willing to take on new challenges and push my boundaries to deliver impactful results.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages:**

- Java
- SQL
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Android programming

## **Web Development Frameworks:**

- React
- Bootstrap

## **Database Management:**

Ability to analyze, design, and implement database structures

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## **Pricing Calculator**

January 2023 - March 2023

- Designed the mockups and UX for the website to get all the list of the course and calculate the price of the course that the user has selected using the REACT and REACT Bootstrap.
- Programmed the application for the user to select the course of their choice and calculate the price.
- Achieved successful implementation where the user could choose any desired course and get the price for the same and book the class.

## **Online Renting App-Staycation**

## August 2022- September 2022

- Developed a user-friendly website allowing renters to easily book their preferred vacation rental, including rooms and villas using advanced Bootstrap
- Enabled renters to customize their booking based on the number of people and rooms needed, with dynamic pricing displayed accordingly.
- Crafted secure online payment options to streamline the rental process for renters.

## **Online Bookstore Website**

July 2022-August 2022

- Created a website for online book purchases, featuring discounted prices and convenient home delivery using HTML, Bootstrap, and CSS
- Designed the UX wireframe for the book-selling website making it dynamic, modern and user friendly for the customers.

 Implemented a book rental feature, offering customers the option to borrow books at a lower cost for a specified period of time

## **EDUCATION**

Programming and Internet technology, Attestation of College Studies

Montreal, Canada January 2022 - August 2023

Collège Universel
Information Technology, Bachelor of Engineering

India

Don Bosco Institute of Technology(DBIT)

June 2014 - June 2018

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Introduction to Databases and SQL Querying** 

Udemy September 2022

Web Design for Web Developer

Udemy February 2021

The Business Intelligence Analyst Course

Udemy January 2021

## **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## **Assistant Manager- Business Analyst**

Mumbai, India

**HDFC** Securities

*April 2021 – January 2022* 

- Implemented the revamped Mutual funds platform used by 20+ million bank customers with a user-friendly and interactive interface
- Co-managed a team of 5 project members that worked towards the identification of application bugs, handling user queries, and testing the application
- Collaborated with 10 bank stakeholders to analyze and validate queries and requirements of users
- Monitored project progress through daily status meetings, weekly reports, and bug reports

Executive - Products Mumbai, India

Angel One Limited

August 2018 – December 2020

- Contributed to revamping the website so as to provide a user-friendly interface.
- Provided technical support for ARQ module, an automated investment engine, wherein the users' query would be addressed immediately, resulting in fewer to zero queries
- Developed and deployed a customer-centric feature that generated a boost in the company's revenue.
- Created a cutting-edge tool enabling investors and traders to filter stocks based on personalized metrics to facilitate efficient stock screening.

## **OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

Team Lead, Part Time Montreal, Canada

Lufa Farm

October 2022 - Present

- Manage a team of 15 warehouse associates in a high-volume fast-paced environment
- Communicate with team members regularly to make them aware of priorities, targets, and operational requirements which resulted in the team's improvement to 70%.
- Monitor inventory levels and identify discrepancies to prevent shortages and overstocking.
- Train and mentor team members on safety protocols and operational procedures